{"tossups": [{"question": "A music video supporting this plan states that when it reaches Puttalam, Sri Lankans won\u2019t have to worry about high power bills. A fund named for this plan is currently being used to construct the Karot Hydropower Project. In his 2016 policy address, Cy Leung mentioned this initiative by name over 40 times. A railway supporting this initiative connects London and Yiwu. Xi Jinping unveiled, for ten points, what massive Chinese infrastructure project that plans to rebuild an ancient trade route?", "answer": "The<b> Belt and Road</b> Initiative (accept<b> One Belt, One Road</b> initiative; accept The Silk Road Economic<b> Belt and</b> 21st century maritime Silk<b> Road</b>; accept Sichou zhi lu jingji<b> dai</b> he 21 shijili haishang sichuo zhi<b> lu</b>; accept Yi<b>dai</b> yi<b>lu</b>; prompt on partial answers)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {"question": "In a political cartoon, this legislation is shown constricting Uncle Sam in front of a group of senators, one of whom is holding a sword labeled \u201cPeanut Dave.\u201d<em> Field v. Clark</em> upheld the legality of a portion of this legislation that allowed the President to \u201csecure reciprocal trade.\u201d After Thomas Reed defeated the sponsor of this law in the 1888 speakership election, Reed named him Chair of the Ways and Means Committee, where he crafted this law. The Wilson-Gorman Tariff replaced, for ten points, what tariff created by the so-called \u201cNapoleon of Protection,\u201d the future 25th President?", "answer": "<b> McKinley</b> Tariff (accept<b> Tariff</b> Act of<b> 1890</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This kingdom subsumed the Mahan Confederacy and had its first capital at Wirye Castle. A king of this nation moved the capital to Sabi and attempted to revive the Gaya Confederacy as a buffer state. This kingdom won a fifth-century war against the Northern Wei dynasty. The Seven-Branched Sword was a gift given to Japan by this kingdom, which was legendarily founded by the sons of Jumong who, after fleeing from Goguryeo [goh-goo-ryuh], settled in the basin of the Han River. For ten points, name this Korean kingdom that was conquered by Silla in 660 AD.", "answer": "<b> Baekje</b> Page 2", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "George Toolson, who he believed he was too good for the minor leagues, unsuccessfully used this law to sue Major League Baseball. William Radovich used this law to sue the NFL after he was blacklisted from signing in the Pacific Coast League. This law was used to uphold the reserve clause in<em> Flood v.</em> <em>Kuhn</em>, which ruled that baseball was interstate commerce and the MLB\u2019s exemption from this law was an\u201canomaly.\u201d The major American sports leagues are exempt from, for ten points, what 1890 law that was successfully used to prosecute Standard Oil and other monopolies?", "answer": "<b> Sherman</b> Antitrust Act (or Law, etc.)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This politician\u2019s brother Wellington became the attorney general of their home state. \u201cRegistration teas\u201d were held during a grassroots campaign for this politician, who derided the other candidates as\u201cseven mediocre men.\u201d In 1917, this politician noted \u201cI want to stand by my country\u201d before making a legislative decision that was criticized as \u201ca fit of female hysteria,\u201d despite 55 other men also voting against entering World War I. For ten points, name this Montana representative, the first woman to serve in Congress.", "answer": "Jeanette<b> Rankin</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This ethnic group was divided into four realms upon the death of Dawaji. This group\u2019s last ruler, Amursana, was the target of a unification campaign by the Qianlong [chee-ahn-long] Emperor that resulted in its genocide. This ethnic group, one of several descended from the Oirats, is the namesake of a basin between the Tian Shan and Altai Mountains, and their namesake \u201cgate\u201d was a key pass along the Silk Road from China into Central Asia. Like the Uyghurs [whee-gurs], this ethnic group was based in modern-day Xinjiang [shin-jee-ahng]. The Mongolian for \u201cleft hand\u201d names, for ten points, what northwestern Chinese ethnic group?", "answer": "<b> Dzungar</b>s (accept<b> Oirat</b> before mentioned, prompt on Mongols) <b>Second Quarter</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This man\u2019s highly critical work<em> The Voices of the Heroic Dead</em> claimed that a leader\u2019s decisions rendered millions of deaths in vain. This founder of the Shield Society asked a gathering crowd \u201cwhy do you defend a constitution that denies you yourself?\u201d while wearing a headband reading \u201cServe the Nation for Seven Lives.\u201d Masakatsu Morita unsuccessfully attempted to behead this man in the aftermath of a raid on the Self-Defense Force\u2019s Ichigaya office. For ten points, name this Japanese author who committed seppuku after a failed 1970 coup.", "answer": "Yukio<b> Mishima</b> (accept names in either order)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "King Alfonso VI the Brave captured Toledo during the Reconquista for, for ten points, what region of northeast Spain that joined with Castile in 1230?", "answer": "<b> Le\u00b4on</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "A holder of this cabinet position was accused of taking kickbacks from A.G. Cattell and sponsored Charles Hall\u2019s re-purposing of the<em> Periwinkle</em> into the<em> Polaris</em>; that man was George Robeson. During the Civil War, this position was held by Gideon Welles. In exchange for his support in the 1896 election, William McKinley appointed Theodore Roosevelt as an assistant to this position. For ten points, name this cabinet position in which capacity Gideon Welles supervised the Anaconda Plan\u2019s blockade of Confederate ports by Union ships.", "answer": "Secretary of the<b> Navy</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "Nikolai Yezhov turned on central heating in this man\u2019s prison cell, accentuating this man\u2019s asthma and causing him to confess. In Lenin\u2019s Testament, this man and Lev Kamenev were accused to be\u201cdeserters\u201d in the \u201cOctober episode.\u201d A \u201csettlement of relations\u201d could \u201cassist in the revolutionizing of the international and British proletariat,\u201d according to a document named for this man that was received by the<em> Daily Mail</em>. For ten points, name this rival of Stalin who supposedly wrote a namesake letter to the British Communist Party that hurt the Labour Party in the 1924 elections.", "answer": "Grigory<b> Zinoviev</b> (accept Hirsch<b> Apfelbaum</b> or Ovsei-Gershon Aronovich<b> Radomyslsky</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "The language of this ethnic group was studied by Antonio Ruiz de Montoya, a Jesuit priest. Father Luis de B\u02dcolanos translated the catechism into the language of these people to further his missionary efforts. Loreto was the first of the reductions that mainly targeted this ethnic group. The Tupi and this ethnic group co-name a major subfamily of South American languages. After encountering this ethnic group, Juan de Ayolas founded Asuncion. For ten points, name this ethnic group that dominated Paraguay before European contact.", "answer": "<b> Guarani</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>Chief Mog was killed in what is now this state, where the Norridgewock Raid took place. Two Northeast Coast Campaigns, the second of which included a defense by Josiah Winslow, targeted this modern-day state during Father Rale\u2019s War. The only American territory of the (+) Mi\u2019kmaq people lay in this state, where Miles Standish led an expedition with the ship</b><em><b> Good Hope</b></em><b>. Colonies by Britain in what is now this state included the (*)</b> Popham and New Ireland colonies. Paul Revere was accused of disobedience and cowardice during a raid on Penobscot Bay in, for ten points, what modern-day state that was did not achieve statehood until the 1820 Missouri Compromise?", "answer": "<b> Maine</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>Felipe de la Garza arrested this man, then let him free, after which he was condemned to death at Padilla. On Good Friday 1814, this man executed 300 prisoners. Gabriel de Yermo\u2019s revolt was put down by this man, who was known as \u201cThe Iron Dragon\u201d and who considered his only loss to be at the Battle of Monte de las Cruces. The United Provinces of (+) Central America declared independence from Spain and the country that this man led. Following this man\u2019s fall from power, Guadalupe Victoria became president. After the Plan of (*) </b> Iguala, this man led the Army of the Three Guarantees. The Treaty of C\u00b4ordoba was signed by Juan de O\u2019Dono\u00b4u and, for ten points, what man who, from 1822 to 1823, was the first emperor of Mexico?", "answer": "Agust\u00b4\u0131n de<b> Iturbide</b> [ee-tur-bih-day] (accept<b> Agustin</b> I; accept<b> Augustine of Mexico</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}], "bonuses": []}